

ANDROID/IOS DEVELOPER

Residence Mariem, Building N°2, Apt N°7, El Mourouj 3, 2074, Ben Arous

□ (+216) 22-230-310 | 🗷 smida.haroun@gmail.com | 🖸 smidaharoun | 📓 haroun-smida | 🛅 harounsmida

"Be the change that you want to see in the world."

Summary.

Determined, passionate, hard-working individual with unyielding self motivation. 3+ years of Android and 2+ year of iOS programming experience combined with a passion for mobile development. Known for good teamwork and leadership skills. Tenacious problem-solver with a strong work ethics. Willing to relocate anywhere

Work Experiences

Orange Tunis, Tunisia

Android/iOS Developer Aug. 2016 - PRESENT

- · Created fully functional applications for Android and iOS & with clear, efficient, well-tested, and maintainable code.
- Contribute and participate in new feature/product specifications.
- Supervised trainees during their graduation projects.
- Provided training sessions in various fields and languages (Swift, Kotlin, Git...).

Technologies: Kotlin, Java, Swift, Objective-C, Git, Scrum, Tuleap, Gitlab

Orange Tunis, Tunisia

INTERN - GRADUATION PROJECT

Feb. 2016 - Jul. 2016

- · Developed universal iOS application (iPhone/iPad) which citizens that provides instant informations and statistics about their municipalities
- Developed a back-end (Laravel)

Technologies: Objective-C, Java, Git, Laravel, Scrum, ActiveColab, Gitlab

Ciblo.net Tunis, Tunisia

INTERN

Feb. 2016 - Mar. 2016

Jun. 2015 - Jul. 2015

• E-COM: Android/Backend e-commerce application based on CMS (prestashop) that allows users to interact with site contents from the android application with the ability to manage it from the backend

Technologies: Android, Java, Prestashop, PHP, REST-API, Git

Education4Sight Tunis, Tunisia

• EDLIGO - Developed an android application for managing teacher lessons and notes.

Technologies: Android, Java, PHP, REST-API, Git

Certificates & Awards

CERTIFICATES

2016 **TOEIC**, Total Score: 940/1000 *Tunis, Tunisia*

AWARDS

2015 **1st place**, ENSIT Startup weekend *Tunis, Tunisia*

Presentation & Training Sessions

Dependency Injection with Dagger 2

Tunis, Tunisia

ORANGE DEVELOPER CENTER

Oct. 2017

• An overview of Denpency Injection with some application in Android.

Inroduction to iOS development with Swift

Tunis, Tunisia Sep. 2017

ORANGE DEVELOPER CENTER

Introduction to Swift syntax, basics and developing iOS application with it.

DECEMBER 1, 2017 HAROUN SMIDA · RÉSUMÉ

Aug. 2017

Orange Developer Center

• Introduction to Android development fundamental and basics..

Portfolio_

Aéroport Tunisie - Android / iOS

Tunis, Tunisia

 Orange
 Jul. 2017 - Oct 2017

- The official application of OACA (Civil Aviation and Airports Authority).
- Provides real-time information of 7 airports (flight status and updates, available services...).

Technologies: Google API, Facebook API, Fabric, Firebase, Volley.

Marsad - Android / iOS Tunis, Tunisia

ORANGE Aug. 2016 - Oct 2016

• Application aims to monitor municipal activity through access to information, and to present it in a clear and updated manner..

Technologies: Objective-C, Laravel, Google API

Artisans d'Art - iOS Tunis, Tunisia

Orange Nov. 2016 - Mar. 2017

• A digital platform for the promotion of trade and artisan products of the Tunisian soil

Technologies: Objective-C, Facebook API, Google API, Firebase, AFNetworking

Concouret - Android Tunis, Tunisia

Personal Nov. 2016

· Application for the lastest job offers in Tunisia

Technologies: Dagger2, Retrofit, Firebase

Other projects Tunis, Tunisia

Orange - Freelance - Personal Aug. 2016 - Oct 2017

- OBD Android/iOS
- Mina7 iOS
- · Wiki for Overwattch Android
- Tunisia Zip Code Android

Program Committees

2017 **Organizer & Coach**, Orange Summer Challenge

2014 **Organizer**, Netlinks Day

Tunis, Tunisia

Tunis, Tunisia

Education

ENSIT(High National School of Engineering of Tunis)

Tunis, Tunisia

ENGINEER'S DEGREE

Sep. 2013 - Jun. 2016

• Speciality: Applied Mathematics and Modeling

FST(Faculty of Sciences of Tunis)

Tunis, Tunisia

PREPARATORY SCHOOL

Sep. 2010 - Jun. 2013

• Speciality: Maths & Physics

References & Links_

Google Play

- Orange Tunisie
- WAPPSTER (Personal)

App Store

• Orange Tunisie

DECEMBER 1, 2017 HAROUN SMIDA · RÉSUMÉ